Orlando Jesig Valverde Arambula

Software Engineer | Full Stack Developer | JavaScript | Rust

orlando.jesig.va@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/septum/ https://qithub.com/septum/



SKILLS

Expert

TypeScript, JavaScript, Node.js, React, Next.js, Docker, HTML, CSS

Advanced

Rust, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Bevy, GitHub Actions, GitLab CI/CD, Linux, Nginx

Familiar

AWS, Terraform, Redis, MongoDB

PROJECTS

septum.io

JAM stack website built with Next.js and Strapi, that leveraged Docker, Terraform, Nginx and Let's Encrypt to make deployments a breeze.

Pushin' Boxes

Clone of the famous game Sokoban written in Rust and Bevy, featuring an in-game level editor and a top-down perspective.

<u>stega</u>

Steganography library and command line tool written in Rust, with an implementation of the least significant bit algorithm.

Bevy UI Bits

Small library of UI components for the Bevy game engine, focused on simplicity and ease of use.

SPOKEN LANGUAGES

Spanish, English

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with over 7 years of professional experience. Designed and implemented a UI editor to manage views on a user facing environment. Created an internal Client Side Rendering JSX framework compatible with React. Expertise in JavaScript. Proficiency with Rust. Generalist by nature.

EDUCATION

Instituto Tecnológico de Durango

Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Information Sciences AUG 2013 - JAN 2020

EXPERIENCE

CloudCAD

Software Engineer

APR 2023 - SEP 2023

 Developed a diagramming focused UI from scratch with modern technologies that replaced the company's PoC frontend, making the development process smooth and its feedback loops tighter.

Applaudo

Full Stack Developer

MAR 2021 - APR 2023

- Developed an Ad Hoc Analysis product in an Analytics Suite that let the user specify data dimensions and filters, presenting the results in charts, tables and reports relevant to the organizations using it.
- Designed and implemented a UI editor to manage views on a user facing environment, allowing users to fulfill their needs by creating and/or editing pages within its application instance.

4plus1Creative

Full Stack Lead Developer

JAN 2018 - MAR 2021

 Created an internal Client Side Rendering JSX framework compatible with React and Next.js components, which was adopted as the default technology to create static content websites.